masters.com 2016-06-13

# Privacy - 2016 Masters Tournament

## Privacy Statement

Effective Date: January 4, 2016 - UPDATED

This Privacy Statement governs the online information collection practices of Augusta National, Inc. ("ANI"). ANI and any and all entities that control, are controlled by, or are affiliated with ANI are collectively referred to herein as "we," "us" or "our". This Privacy Statement is part of the Terms of Use and outlines the types of information that we gather about you while you are using Masters.com (the "Site") and other sites controlled or managed by ANI, and the ways in which we use and don't use this information. This Privacy Statement does not apply to information that we may collect offline or through other means (for example, at a live event, via telephone, or through the mail).

 **PLEASE READ THIS PRIVACY STATEMENT AND OURTERMS OF USE CAREFULLY BEFORE USING THE SITE. DO NOT USE THE SITE OR PROVIDE INFORMATION (OR ALLOW OTHERS TO DO SO ON YOUR BEHALF) IF YOU (AND YOUR PRINCIPAL IF YOU ARE ACTING AS AGENT) DO NOT AGREE WITH ALL OF THE TERMS OF USE, INCLUDING THIS PRIVACY STATEMENT AND ANY APPLICABLE SUPPLEMENTAL PRIVACY STATEMENTS.** By using the Site, you signify your agreement to this Privacy Statement and our terms of use. If you do not agree to this Privacy Statement and the Terms of Use, you may not use the Site.

 **1\. CHANGES TO THE PRIVACY STATEMENT**

Please note that we may change this Privacy Statement from time to time by posting an updated version of the Privacy Statement to the Site. It is your obligation to review this Privacy Statement from time to time and to review updates that are posted on the Site. If we make a material change to the way in which we collect, use, or share your personal information, we will post the changes on this page. If the changes are significant, we will provide a more prominent notice. Please refer to this Privacy Statement regularly. Your use of the Site following any such notice will signify and constitute your assent to and acceptance of the revised Privacy Statement.

If we make a material change to the way in which we collect, use, and/or share your personal information, we will post the changes on this page. If the changes are significant, we will provide a more prominent notice. Please refer to this policy regularly. Your use of the Site following any such notice will signify and constitute your assent to and acceptance of the revised Privacy Statement.

 **2\. THE INFORMATION WE GATHER AND HOW WE USE IT**

 **A. Information we collect**

Non-personally identifiable information is information that does not identify an individual user of the Site. We may use non-personally identifiable information collected from you and other users to perform statistical analyses of user behavior and characteristics. These aggregated statistics may be used to improve the Site and for product development and marketing purposes generally. We also may provide such aggregated information to advertisers, sponsors, licensees, and other existing or potential ANI vendors for certain purposes, but such statistics contain no personally identifiable information and cannot be used to gather such information.

"Personally identifiable information" is identifiable information about an individual person, as more particularly described under applicable privacy laws, such as a name, email address, and age. The personally identifiable information you provide to us when using the Site may be used to provide ANI or Masters products and services to you, to enhance your experience at the Site, and, if applicable, to enhance your experience as a subscriber to ANI's products and services. For example, you may register to create a Masters.com account profile (and you may be required do so to use payment features). You will need to supply your email address, a password, and the other information required for an account. When you register, Site features may allow you to provide additional information. For example, you may purchase, use, or load certain credit card information into the Site or provide preferences related to offers and incentives that we and our affiliates might offer. The information you decide to include may be synchronized between the Site and the App so that you may have access to it from several devices. 

**B. How we use information we collect**

Our Site also collects information through a variety of technical methods, including without limitation, cookies, web beacons, and other technologies. Cookies are pieces of information that a Web site sends to your computer while you are viewing the Web site. Web beacons are small pieces of data that are embedded in images on the pages of Web sites. Cookies, web beacons, and other technical methods may involve the transmission of information either directly to us or to another party authorized by us to collect information on our behalf. We use these technologies for a variety of purposes such as to improve your on-line experience, to manage Site traffic, to prevent, detect, and investigate fraud, to assess promotional effectiveness, to track information such as the total number of visitors, IP addresses and browser types, access times, pages viewed and referring website addresses. We may also employ these technologies so that we remember you when you return to the Site, and collect information about your activities on the Site. We may also deliver ads or make recommendations in the context of your current visit to our Site or a single search query in our Site.

We generally do not share information from "cookies" and the like with third parties other than our service providers and within the ANI organization, but reserve the right to do so. For example, we may share information from "cookies" or other technologies used on our Site with our service providers or within the ANI, on an aggregate basis or to facilitate our business or marketing purposes (or those of our affiliated entities). If we materially change the type of information we automatically collect or the ways in which we share it, we will notify you.

If you do not want to receive cookies, you may set your browser to reject them. However, if you turn cookies off, you may not have access to some of the Site's services and features. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies when you access the Site.

ANI uses the personally identifiable information you provide to us (i) for our business purposes, such as establishing and managing your customer account, providing products and services you request (such as processing and shipping orders and sending order and shipping confirmations), processing and collecting payments; (ii) to provide customer support, and to send you important administrative communications regarding the Site; (iii) to evaluate and improve our business, including developing new products and services and analyzing the effectiveness of products, services, and the Site; (iv) to perform data analyses, including market and consumer search, trend analysis, demographic analysis, and financial analysis; (v) to comply with applicable legal requirements, to enforce our policies and terms of service, and to protect you, the Site, and us, against error and fraud. In addition, we may use your personally identifiable information to contact you concerning offers and new products and to enhance our product offerings. You may also be asked on the Site whether you wish to receive information from third parties and upon your consent, ANI and such third parties may use the personally identifiable information you provide to contact you consistent with the consent you provided.

We may employ independent contractors, vendors, and suppliers (collectively, "Outside Contractors") to provide specific services and products related to ANI and the Site, including, without limitation, hosting and maintaining the Site, and developing applications for the Site. These Outside Contractors may receive access to information collected from you, including your personally identifiable information, in the course of providing products or services to us. 

We may disclose your personal information to third parties in connection with a corporate transaction, where all or a portion of our business or assets (including our associated customer lists containing your personal information) are sold or transferred. We may also disclose your personal information if disclosure is required by law or pursuant to judicial or governmental investigations or proceedings.

In addition to the foregoing uses, if you submit, post, email or otherwise send us information, content or materials, including, without limitation, photographs, remarks, suggestions, ideas or comments (collectively, "Submissions"), we (and our licensees, distributors, agents, representatives and other authorized users) shall be entitled to unrestricted use of such information in accordance with our Terms of Use. Please click here to read the Terms of Use. To the extent Submissions contain any personal information, we cannot protect such information as confidential, and third parties may collect and use such information. We do not pay or provide other consideration for any Submissions (including but not limited to those regarding business or restaurant processes or procedures, product ideas, marketing or advertising slogans, or improvement of products, the Site or content thereon), graphics, or other information communicated through this Site

You should be aware that if you voluntarily disclose personally identifiable information in an e-mail or other communications with third parties listed on the Site or in other materials, that information, along with any other information disclosed in your communication, can be collected and correlated and used by such third parties and may result in your receiving unsolicited messages from other persons. Such collection, correlation, use, and messages are beyond our control.

This Privacy Statement applies to ANI's treatment of personally identifiable information collected by or on behalf of ANI through the Site and does not necessarily reflect practices with respect to information gathered through other sites that we operate or through other off-line means. The Privacy Statement does not apply to practices of companies whose sites may be linked to the Site. For access to the privacy policies of those linked sites, please refer to the policies and practices provided by those sites at their home pages.

 **3\. SPECIAL NOTE FOR PARENTS CONCERNING PRIVACY**

The Site is considered a general audience site and is not directed to children. ANI does not currently knowingly collect any personal information from children under the age of thirteen on the Site. If you are under 18, you may use the Site only with the involvement of a parent or legal guardian. If in the future, we collect personally identifiable information from children, we will do so in compliance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (15 U.S.C. 6501 et seq.) including, without limitation, obtaining necessary parental consent.

 **4\. USE OF COOKIES**

ANI uses cookies to enhance the interactive nature of your Internet experience and to provide a convenient feature to save you time. "Cookies" are small text files that your web browser leaves on your hard drive to recognize you as a repeat user of our Site, track your use of our Site and target advertising. Cookies enable ANI to quickly retrieve specific information from previous visits and to recall features that you may have customized on your browser. You can disable Cookies using your Internet browser settings. Note that if you disable Cookies, certain features of our Site may not function properly.

 **5\. SECURITY**

ANI employs what we believe are commercially reasonable efforts to provide reasonable procedural and technical safeguards for your personally identifiable information against loss, theft, alteration, and unauthorized access, use and disclosure where we are legally required to protect it, but this is not a promise that your information will never be disclosed except as provided herein. However, the nature of the Internet is such that information may be transmitted over networks without appropriate security measures and may be accessed, deleted, altered, used or disclosed by unauthorized persons. WE DO NOT GUARANTEE THE SECURITY OF PERSONAL INFORMATION OR OTHER INFORMATION IN ANY FORM. Information can sometimes be intercepted or accessed in violation of law, contract, or policy, and technologies do not always work as anticipated.

Because of the international nature of the services and products provided by this Site and the nature of ANI's business, your personally identifiable information may, subject to applicable law, be transferred internationally throughout ANI worldwide for the purposes described above. This may mean that personally identifiable information is transferred to countries which do not have laws or regulations which protect personally identifiable information, such as the United States, where the server for this Site is located.

 **6\. CONSENT; OPT-OUT**

In addition to consenting to the Terms of Use, including this Privacy Statement (and any relevant supplemental policies), we want you to know and we request your particular consent to, a few activities relating to personal information that will help us to deal with personal information that is disclosed in furtherance of our operations and programs. These are described immediately below.

 **A. Consent to Share and Disclose Personal Information, Including Data Transfers Internationally**

We may share information within the ANI organization, including our subsidiaries and affiliates. We may also share information with companies that provide support services to us (such as credit card processors, mailing houses, web hosts, technical support providers, fulfillment centers, or other services or for enforcing or investigating transactions or business operations). These companies may need information about you in order to perform their functions. These companies are not authorized to use the information we share with them for any other purpose, but we do not control these companies. You agree that ANI and those with whom we share personal information (" **Recipients** ") may disclose and transfer your personal information worldwide (including in and outside the U.S, Canada, the European Union, and other jurisdictions) for any purpose relating to our operations, programs, or otherwise that is not allowed or prohibited by this Privacy Statement. ANI may transfer information that you send to us, including without limitation, personally identifiable information, to countries that do not provide the same level of legal data protection as the country from which you access this Site. By using this Site, you consent to such transfers and to the processing by ANI of such information as described in this Privacy Statement.

 **B. Consent to Electronic Notice If There is a Security Breach**

If we or a Recipient is required to provide notice of unauthorized access or other invasion of certain security systems, you agree that we (or they) may do so when required (or voluntarily) by posting notice on our Site or sending notice to any email address we have for you, in our (or their) good faith discretion. You agree that notice to you will count as notice to others for whom you are acting, and agree to pass the notice on to them.

 **C. Opt Out**

If you supply ANI with your email address, you may receive periodic electronic mailings from us regarding news, products, services, or upcoming events. If you ever wish to stop receiving such emails, please e-mail us at postmaster@augustanational.com with the phrase "REMOVE ME FROM MAILINGS" in the subject line. Please know that such a decision will not stop advertising or content that is generated prior to the time when we can accomplish the removal of your personally identifiable information.

 **7\. QUESTIONS, ACCESS, CONTACT INFORMATION, CHOICE, AND CORRECTION**

If you have any questions or concerns about our Privacy Statement, email us at postmaster@augustanational.com with the phrase "MASTERS.COM PRIVACY STATEMENT" in the subject line, call 706-667-6000, or send your questions or concerns in writing to:

Augusta National, Inc.  
2604 Washington Rd.  
Augusta, Georgia 30904 

No person (of any age) is required to provide us with the personally identifiable information we request. If you do not wish to provide your personally identifiable information, you are free not to do so. Your provision of requested personally identifiable to us through our Site or other means is presumed by us to be voluntary and with your consent to the uses described herein. However, in some cases, only persons who provide the requested personally identifiable information will be able to participate in the Site activities and offerings.

If you request, we will provide you with the opportunity to object to and correct any inaccurate information we maintain about you collected by the Site, subject to verification, as well as to require us to delete your personally identifiable information if you no longer want us to process it. Any such request may be added to your data file and forwarded to data recipients where appropriate or requested by you. You may also request that your data not be shared with any third parties. Such requests may be made by contacting us in accordance with this section.

 **8\. CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS**

California Civil Code Section 1798.83, also known as the "Shine The Light" law, permits our users who are California residents to request and obtain from us once a year, free of charge, information about the personal information (if any) we disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes. If applicable, this information would include a list of the categories of personal information that was shared and the names and addresses of all third parties with which we shared information in the immediately preceding calendar year. California customers who wish to request further information about our compliance with this law or have questions or concerns about our privacy practices and policies may contact us in writing as set forth in Section 7 (Questions, Access, Contact Information, Choice, and Enforcement).

 **9\. SUPPLEMENTAL PRIVACY STATEMENT-MOBILE APPS**

This Supplemental Privacy Statement - Mobile Apps ("App Statement") supplements the Augusta National, Inc. Privacy Statement ("Privacy Statement"). This App Statement (as well as the main Privacy Statement) applies if you download or use The Official Masters Tournament App or any mobile application that we offer (alone or with others) (each, an "App") from time to time for download, such as on the Site, or through a third party platform (such as the Apple iTunes store or Google Play, etc.). Additionally, wherever the Privacy Statement uses the term "Site," that term is defined in the Privacy Statement to include all Apps.

This App Statement is part of our Privacy Statement, which is part of our Terms of Use. Terms used but not defined in this App Statement are defined in those documents. **DOWNLOADING OR USING AN APP, CREATING AN ACCOUNT PROFILE, OR AFFIRMATIVELY SUBMITTING ANY PERSONAL INFORMATION THROUGH AN APP WILL BE YOUR CONSENT TO OUR TERMS OF USE, INCLUDING OUR PRIVACY STATEMENT (WHICH INCLUDES THIS APP STATEMENT), ALL AS AMENDED FROM TIME TO TIME.**

 **A. Information Automatically Collected by Apps**

When you download or use an App, personal information about you or the device that you use in connection with the App may automatically be collected by us or by third parties. This may include, for example, information about your download or use of the App, unique device identifiers associated with the device(s) you use to download or use the App, or information associated with equipment or systems used in connection with your device (e.g., an identifier of a Wi-Fi router or Internet access point). Third parties may also obtain information, such as your mobile device manufacturer or carrier, mobile or data network systems or operators, other providers of other apps or code on your device, and anyone who has administrative privileges to devices you use. In general, we do not control what information those kinds of third parties may receive and do not take any steps affirmatively to provide them with more information than they would obtain from other apps you might choose to download.

You may also be reminded by the app "store" (e.g., a third party platform you might use to obtain the App, such as Apple iTunes store or Google Play, etc.) that certain information might be sought by us or others, or that certain privacy policies will apply to an App. You agree that we may rely upon any consents or agreements you provide to such stores or device manufacturers (e.g., if you tell them that it’s okay that an App collect "location" or other personal information, we may rely on your consent as if you had given it directly to us).

 **B. Additional Information Collected in Apps**

In addition to the types of personal information that we collect on the Site generally, additional information may be collected in an App. For example, App features may allow you to provide additional information such as location preferences. The information you decide to include may be synchronized between the Site and the App so that you may have access to it from several devices.

 **C. Updates to, and Deletion of, Information**

You may update some information (not all of which will necessarily be personal information) provided to an App by using any functionality in the App for that. You can remove Apps by deleting or uninstalling them from all of devices they are on. Properly removing the App will stop your device from providing further information to us or others, but will not affect information already collected or Disclosed, including information that resides somewhere else. For example, our App may synchronize with your account profile on the Site (and vice versa) and the Site information for such account profiles is held by us. To eliminate that information, you will need to edit your account profile information on the Site as described in Section 7 (Questions, Access, Contact Information, Choice, and Correction). Additionally, because of the way we maintain account profiles, residual copies of account profile, App, and other associated information may remain on our backup systems. Also, App or information removal (full or partial) will not have any effect on information already disclosed or relied upon by us or others.

 **D. How We Use Information Collected in Apps**

In addition to the uses of personal information allowed in the Privacy Statement, we make these kinds of uses of personal information collected in an App. We disclose it:

  * to the rest of our Site and as provided with respect to the rest of the Site, and we combine it with information that we collect on, through or in connection with the Site;
  * for marketing purposes and to help us improve products and services, including to send you emails and other communications if you’ve created an account profile on the Site; and
  * to our affiliates and other third parties or persons who assist with the operation of an App, the rest of the Site, or app stores.

 **E. Consent to Share and Disclose Personal Information**

In addition to consenting to the Terms of Use and Privacy Statement, you agree that by using an App or providing personal information in the App, you are consenting to the collection, retention, use, and disclosure of your information in accordance with the terms of this App Statement and the Privacy Statement. You also agree that you are consenting to disclosure of your information to third parties as stated in this App Statement (e.g., see the How We Use Information Collected in Apps section above).

 **F. Security**

The "Security" section of our Privacy Statement and the "Registration Information and Security" section of our Terms of Use provides information about our general security. Apps use mobile phones and other devices, and any security of data that resides on the device will only be as secure as the device itself. Please be advised, however, that the transmission of information over wireless and wired networks is not inherently secure and, although we endeavor to provide reasonable security measures, no security system can prevent all potential security breaches. As a result, your information may be subject to interception or loss which is beyond our control.
